Guide to the Oskar Morgenstern Papers, 1866-1992 and undated RL.10033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1910-1977 and undated
  - Alphabetical
    - Experiment and Computation in Economics, 1952-1953, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Fide Sed Ante Fide, Remarks to Mr. R. T. Bowman's 'Comments,'" 1964 (Box 25)
    - Foreward, 1974 (Energy Problems) (Box 25)
    - Foreword for Michio Hatanaka's book, undated (Box 100)
    - Francis Y. Edgeworth, 1927 (Box 25)
    - Friedliche Kernexplosionen und der Uebergang von Privaten zu Offentlichen Investitionen, 1966: 1966-1967, undated (Box 25)
    - Further Consideration of 'An Open Expanding Economy Model,' 1971: 1970-1971 (Box 25)
    - Game Theory, Dictionary of the History of Ideas, 1973: 1961-1973, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - "Game Theory" Addenda for International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968-1975 (Box 25)
    - "Game Theory" and "John von Neumann" for International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1963-1966, undated (Box 25)
    - Game Theory Article Addition for Encyclopedia of Statistics, 1975: 1974-1977 (Box 25)
    - Games Which Are Equivalent to Some Models of Exchange, 1969-1975 (Box 25)
    - Zur gegenwrtigen Konjunkturlage sterreichs, 1937 (Box 26)
    - General Report on the Economics of the Peaceful Uses of Underground Nuclear Explosions, 1967, Morgenstern and Heiss (Box 26)
    - A Generalization of the von Neumann Model of an Expanding Economy, 1956: 1955-1956 (Box 26)
    - German Economy, A Free Trade System, Rules for Industrial Control Proposed, 1947 (Box 26)
    - Gold in Europe, 1951 (Box 26)
    - Goran Nyblen, The Problem of Summation in Economic Science, 1951 (Box 26)
    - A Graph Oriented Model for Research Management, 1966: 1965-1966 (Box 26)
    - Graz Lecture, 1966 (Box 100)
    - Die Grenzen der Wirtschaftspolitik, 1934: Typescript (?) (Box 26)
    - How to Plan to Beat Hell, undated (Box 26)
    - Insiders and Outsiders in Industrial Research, 1969 (Box 26)
    - Inflation and the New Administration, circa 1953 (Box 26)
    - An Intellectual Disaster, 1975 (Vietnam) (Box 26)
    - The International Spread of Business Cycles, undated (Box 26)
    - Inventory Cycles Acceleration, Lectures and Notes, 1961, undated (Box 26)
    - International Financial Transactions (1959): Review (Box 26)
    - International vergleichende Konjunkturforschung, 1927: 1926-1928 (Box 26)
    - Konjunct Vertrag, 1936 (Box 26)
    - Konjunktur, Wrung und Notenbankpolitik, s.s 1933" (Folder Label) (Box 26)
    - Large Scale Computation in Economics, undated (Box 26)
    - Leading Economic Thinkers of Their Times, 1946 (Box 26)
    - Lecture and Materials on Bargaining, undated (Box 100)
    - Letter for Forum for Contemporary History, 1974 (Box 26)
    - The Life Span of the Works of Man, 1956 (Notes) (Box 26)
    - Limiti E Condizioni Dei Programmi Economici, undated (Box 100)
    - The Limits of Economics, 1933 (Box 27)
    - Livermore Labs,1968 (Box 100)
    - Logistik und Sozialwissenshaften, 1936 (Box 27)
    - Long Term Planning with Models of Static and Dynamic Open Expending Economies, 1974: 1972-1974 (Box 27)
    - Luigi Amoroso, 1963 (Box 100)
    - Die Macht im Handel der Staaten; Ein Problem der Theorie des Internationalen Handels, 1963 (Predhl Festschrift) (Box 27)
    - Mathematical Economics, 1931 (Box 27)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies (1976): Master Copy for Printer with Corrections (Box 27)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies, Morgenstern and Thompson (1976): Proofs and Notes, 1969-1975 (Chaps. 1-10, part of 13) (Box 27)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies (1976): Title Page, Table of Contents, Preface (Box 27)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies (1976), Chapter 1, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies (1976): Chapters 2-15 (Box 28)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies (1976): Appendices, bibliography, etc. (Box 29)
    - Merkle Memorial Lecture, Livermore, Cal, 1968 (Box 100)
    - "The Military Payment Certificate System" and Letter to Editor of New York Times on same subject, 1954-1955 (Box 29)
    - Model of Economy, 1952 (Box 100)
    - Nature and Uses of Data and Methods, undated (Box 29)
    - New York Times Paper,1960 (Box 100)
    - Norddeutscher Rundfunk Game Theory Lecture,1966 (Box 100)
    - Note on the Formulation of the Stud of Logistics, undated (Box 100)
    - Observations on the Problem of the American Institutionalists, undated (Box 100)
    - Oekonometrische Berechnungen im Grossen, 1952 (Box 29)
    - sterrereiches Institut fr Wirtschaftsforschung, 1977 (Articles on) (Box 29)
    - Offene Probleme der Kosten-und Ertragstheorie, 1931: 1929-1934 (Box 29)
    - Oligopoly, Competition and the Theory of Games, 1947 (Box 29)
    - On Some Criticisms of Game Theory, undated (Box 100)
    - On the Accuracy of Economic Observations, 1950-1965, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - On the Accuracy of Economic Observations: Book Reviews and New Material, 1960-1969 (Box 29)
    - An Open Expanding Economy Model, 1969: 1969-1972 (Box 30)
    - Paper on Eisenbahn und Auto In Oesterreich, 1936 (Box 100)
    - Philadelphia Paper Limits to the Use of Mathematics, 1962 (Box 101)
    - Precision et incertitude des donnes conomiques: Reviews and Notices, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Predictability of Stock Market Prices, 1970: Papers Concerning, 1971-1975 (Box 30)
    - Preface to Russian Edition of the Theory of Games and Economic Behavior,1967 (Box 101)
    - Die Preistheorie von Gustav Cassel, 1924-1925 (Box 30)
    - Preliminary Observations on the Rate of Growth of the American Economy, 1950 (Box 101)
    - Prices (Topic), 1928 (Box 30)
    - Price, Utility, Economic Necessity (Topics), 1920s-1930s (Box 30)
    - Private and Public Consumption and Savings in the von Neumann Model of an Expanding Economy, 1967: 1967-1974 (Box 30)
    - Prolegomena to a Theory of Organization, 1951: (Box 30)
    - Qualitative and Quantitative Konjunkturforschung, 1928: 1926-1928 (Box 31)
    - The Question of National Defense, 1959: Draft: Table of Contents - Chap. IV (Box 31)
    - The Question of National Defense, 1959: Draft: Chaps. V-IX and Epilogue, and letter (1974), review (1960) (Box 31)
    - Qui Numerare Incipit Errare Incipit, 1963: Morgenstern's Reply to Raymond T. Bowman's Article Concerning It, 1963-1964 (Box 31)
    - The Random-Walk Hypothesis of Stock Market Behavior, 1963: 1962-1963 (Box 31)
    - Rationality-Limited Means of Violence, 1960 (Box 101)
    - Reader Digest Paper, 1960 (Box 101)
    - Reconsideration of Deterrence, 1971 (Box 31)
    - Regulierte Wirtschaft, 1937 (Box 31)
    - Remarks at International Studies Conference, Paris, 1937 (Box 31)
    - Remarks at Warsaw Conference, July, 1972 (Box 31)
    - Remarks for the Discussion of Input-Output Studies, Cleveland, 1948 (Box 31)
    - Resume of a Speech on the U.S. Economy (German),1965 (Box 101)
    - Review of Alex Rubner's Three Sacred Cows of Economics, 1972 (Box 31)
    - Review of The Economists by Leonard Silk, 1977: 1976-1977 (Box 31)
    - Review of Enrico Barone's Grundzge der Theoretischen Nationalkonomie..., 1927 (Box 31)
    - Review of International Trade Statistics, Allen and Ely, 1955 (Box 31)
    - Review of Kurt Zimmerman's Das Krisenproblem in der Neuren Nationalkonomischen Theorie, 1927 (Box 31)
    - Review of Otto Khne's Die Mathematische Schule in der Nationalkonomie, 1930 (Box 31)
    - Review of A Survey of Contemporary Economics, 1953 (Box 31)
    - Review of Wilhelm Vleugels' Das Ende der Grenznutzentheorie? Eine Auseinandersetzung mit Franz Oppenheimer, 1925 (Box 31)
    - Reviews of Joseph Schumpeter's Business Cycles, 1940-1941 (Box 31)
    - Rutgers State University Lecture, 1965 (Box 101)
    - Schwedischer Brief, 1921 (Box 31)
    - Second Stockmarket Paper (with Godfrey and Grauger), 1963 (Box 101)
    - Selected Economic Writings of Oskar Morgenstern, 1974-1976, undated (Box 31)
    - Sociology and the Theory of Games, 1952: 1951-1952, undated (Box 31)
    - Solution of Abraham Wald's Problem, 1945 (Box 31)
    - Some Critical Points in Contemporary Economic Theory, 1950-1971 (Box 31)
    - Some Critical Points in Economic Theory,1970 (Box 101)
    - Some Economic Results of Space Exploration, 1968 (Box 31)
    - Some Reflections on Utility, 1976: 1974-1976 (Box 32)
    - Some Thoughts Bearing on National Defense Policy, 1958, undated (Box 32)
    - Some Thoughts on Maxims of Behavior in a Dynamic Environment, 1976: 1975-1976 (Box 32)
    - Some Unsettled Problems of Business Cycle Research (First Draft), 1940-1942 (Box 32)
    - Spectral Analysis of New York Stock Market Prices, Morgenstern and Granger, 1963: 1963-1964, undated (Box 32)
    - Spieltheorie und Wirtschaftswissenschaft, 1963: 1964-1965 (Box 32)
    - Squeeze on Japan, Depression Threatens as Exports Dwindle and Food Import Needs Rapidly Increase, 1954 (Box 32)
    - The Stability of Inverses of Input-Output Matrices, 1950 (Box 32)
    - Der Stand und die nchste Zukunft der Konjunkturforschung, 1933: 1932 (Box 32)
    - Statement Regarding the Problem of Objectivity, Freedom from Indoctrinating Methods, etc., in the Teaching of Economics, 1947 (Box 32)
    - Statements of Some Problems in Assignment of Personnel to Jobs,1950 (Box 101)
    - Stock Price RM with Grauger,1962 (Box 101)
    - Strategic Allocation of Integral Games, 1971 (Box 32)
    - Strategie-Heute, 1962 (Box 32)
    - Strategische Aspekte Der Spieltheorie,1966 (Box 101)
    - A Study of Power Based on the Theory of Games of Strategy, undated (Box 32)
    - Symmetrical Solutions of General n-Person Games, 1961 (1946): 1958-1976, undated (Box 32)
    - Talk to High School Students on Economic Theory,1964 (Box 101)
    - Thailand, 1954 (Box 32)
    - Der Theoretische Unterbau der Wirtschaftspolitik, 1956-1957 (Box 32)
    - Zur Theorie der Productionsperiode, 1935 (Box 32)
    - Die Theorie der Spiele und des Wirtschaftlichen Verhaltens, 1950: 1950-1951, undated (Box 32)
    - Theory of Games and Economic Behavior, 1948, for Scientific American (Box 32)
    - Theory of Games and Economic Behavior: Publication, etc., 1973-1974, undated (Box 32)
    - "Theory of Games and Economic Behavior" miscellaneous notes, handwritten, undated (Box 32)
    - Theory of Games and Economic Behavior publisher correspondence re: sales, reprinting, 1969-1971 (Box 32)
      Scope and Contents
      Folder of Morgenstern's sales figures, royalty statements, and other ephemera also included. All given to Martin Shubik by Morgenstern, who was his advisor. This folder of material was acquired as a gift from Martin Shubik as part of Acc. 2018-0050.
    - Theory: Art-Jewel Market,1955 (Box 101)
    - Theses and Problems for the Discussion of Limited War, undated (Box 101)
    - Thirteen Critical Points in Contemporary Economic Theory: An Interpretation, 1972: 1950-1974, undated (Box 32)
    - Thoughts and Memories, 1974 (Box 33)
    - Time Factor in the Theory of Value, undated (Box 101)
    - The Time Moment in Value Theory, 1933 and later (Box 33)
    - Torpa, Ein Schwedischer Adelssitz, 1922 (Box 33)
    - Toward a Social Minimax, A Conversation with Oskar Morgenstern, by Gerald Silverberg, 1972 (Box 33)
    - The Transformation of Abstract Knowledge into Doctrine, 1968 (Box 33)
    - Die Tschechoslowakei in Schwedischem Lichte, 1922 (Box 33)
    - Uber die Genauigkeit Wirtschaftlicher Beobachtungen, 1965: 1966 (Box 33)
    - Uber Ratenzahlungen, 1926 (Box 33)
    - University of Rochester Lecture, 1962 (Box 101)
    - Value of the U.S. Space Program,1962 (Box 101)
    - Vienna Speech, 1973: Notes, 1962-1977, undated (Box 33)
    - Vollkommene Voraussicht und Wirtschaftliches Gleichgewicht, 1935 (Box 33)
    - Waffenschmidt Paper, 1966 (Box 101)
    - Wall Street Journal Articles, 1952-1953, undated (Box 33)
    - Wall Street Journal Royster, Vermont, undated (Box 101)
    - Wall Street Journal Series, 1951-1952 (Box 33)
    - Washington Statistical Soceity Lecture, 1965 (Box 101)
    - Weapons, Targets and Doctrine, undated (Box 101)
    - When Is a Problem of Economic Policy Solvable?, 1953, undated (Box 33)
    - Wirtschaftsprognose (1928), New Edition, 1976: 1936-1976 (Box 33)
    - Wirtschaftsprognose (1928), New Introduction, 1976: 1936-1976, undated (Box 33)
    - Wirtschaftsprognose (1928): Reviews, 1928-1929, undated (Box 33)
    - Worth of the Space Program: Economics, undated (Box 101)
    - Wrterbuch der Okon. Theorie, Plane, etc., 1930-1938 and undated (Box 33)
    - Das Zeitmoment in der Wertlehre, 1934, undated (Box 33)
    - Zentralvereinigung der Architekten Osterreichs, 1967 (Box 101)
    - Dem Zufall Eine Chance Geben, Ein Portrt des Nationalkonomen Morgenstern, Transcript from Film by Theo Parker and Christian Grote, 1972 (Box 33)
- Subject Files Series, 1893-1987 and undated
  The bulk of this series consists of files for persons, topics, and organizations relating to Morgenstern's career as an economic theorist, educator, author, and government advisor, and his concern for the evaluation and solution of national and international economic problems. The files include letters, writings by Morgenstern and others, printed material, photocopies, notes, memoranda, lecture notes, mathematics, bibliography, reports, pictures, and undergraduate and graduate course material. Arranged alphabetically.
  A later addition to Morgenstern's Subject Files has been incorporated into the list below but is physically housed separately in Boxes 94-99.
  - Accuracy of Economic Observations, 1967-1974, undated (Box 34)
  - Adaptation of Graph Theory, 1965 (Box 94)
  - Adirondack Park Preservation, 1971-1976, undated (Box 34)
  - Aerospace Technology and National Needs, 1975 (Box 34)
  - Aggegate Expenditure Statistics, 1971 (Box 94)
  - Aggregation in Input-Output Analysis, 1957 (Box 94)
  - AIAA Meeting- Amaheim, Cal., 1967 (Box 94)
  - Air Force File I, undated (Box 94)
  - Air Force File II, undated (Box 94)
  - Alchemy, Astronomy, and Economics, 1943-1950 (Box 34)
  - Allied Social Science Associations, 1976 (Box 34)
  - AMC Redstone Arsenal 1969-1971 (Box 94)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1976-1977 (Box 34)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Section on History and Philosophy of Science, 1971 (Box 34)
  - American Economic Association, 1963-1970 (Box 94)
  - American Economic Association, 1976-1977 (Box 34)
  - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, 1969-1974 (Box 34)
  - American Economic Review, 1938-1941 (Box 34)
  - American Specialists Pogram Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, 1965 (Box 94)
  - American Statistical Association, 1964 (Box 94)
  - Annual Computer Application Symp. Of N.U. Soceity of Security Analysts, New York, 1970 (Box 94)
  - Arab Funds, 1974 (Box 35)
  - Armed Forces Industrial College Seminar, 1949 (Box 35)
  - Arms Control and Disarmament, 1960-1974, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Ashby of Brandon, Lord. "A Second Look at Doom, 1975 (Box 35)
  - Awards/ Honors, 1969 (Box 94)
  - Austria, 1937-1938, undated (Box 35)
  - Austria, 1974-1977 (Box 35)
  - Austrian Relief: Wilhelm Morgenstern and Others, 1943-1947, undated (Box 36)
  - Austrian Scholars, 1972-1976 (Box 36)
  - Ballinger Publishing Co., 1972-1976, undated (Box 36)
  - Basic Science, 1970-1977, undated (Box 36)
  - Baumol, William J., undated (Box 36)
  - Bedaux Companies, 1972-1974 (Box 36)
  - Bergedorfer Gesprachskreis, 1964-1966 (Box 94)
  - Bielefeld Conference (Problems of Game Theory), 1974, undated (Box 36)
  - Blin, Jean-Marie, 1974-1976, undated (Box 36)
  - BLS Worksheets- Trade Margin Information, undated (Box 94)
  - Boillot, Claude E., and Suez Companies, 1971-1976 (Box 36)
  - Borch, Karl: "The Monster in Loch Ness, 1976 (Box 36)
  - Brams, Steven, J., 1975-1977 (Box 36)
  - Brooklyn College Lecture, 1966 (Box 94)
  - Budapest Meetings- June 1963 (Box 94)
  - Budget, 1972-1974 (Box 36)
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1947-1952 (Box 94)
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics, Wash D.C., 1967 (Box 94)
  - Burley, S. Peter, 1971-1972 (Box 36)
  - Burns, Eve, 1926-1927, undated (Box 36)
  - Business Cycles: Agriculture and Natural Phenomena, 1934-1954 (Box 37)
  - Business Cycles: Economics 314, 1938-1962, undated (Box 37)
  - Business Cycles: Historical material, 1943-1959, undated (Box 37)
  - Business Cycles: Model Sequences, etc. (Lundberg, Kalecki, etc.), undated (Box 37)
  - Business Cycles: Policy, 1938-1961, undated (Box 37)
  - Business Cycles: Theory, 1960 (Box 37)
  - Business Cycles and Public Debt, 1957-1960, undated (Box 37)
  - California, 1972-1974, undated (Box 37)
  - Campus Wold, Inc., undated (Box 94)
  - Carnegie Endowment, 1938 (Box 94)
  - Century Club, 1971-1973, undated (Box 37)
  - Chas. Scribner's Sons Dictionary of the History of Ideas, 1967-1970 (Box 94)
  - Chicago Symposium, 1965-1966 (Box 94)
  - Civil Defense, 1963 (Box 37)
  - Colantoni, Claude S., undated (Box 37)
  - Compression, 1954, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Computing Machines, undated (Box 94)
  - Conair I, 1959-1962 (Box 94)
  - Conair II, 1959-1962 (Box 94)
  - Conair III, 1959-1962 (Box 94)
  - Conference on Application of Game Theory, 1966 (Box 94)
  - Conference on Computers Institute- Vienna ,1967 (Box 94)
  - Conference: Programs and Participants, 1959-1962 (Box 94)
  - Conferences on the Unity of the Sciences, 1974-1976, undated (Box 37)
  - Constants in Economics, 1955-1965, undated (Box 37)
  - Consumer Demand, 1973-1975 (Box 37)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1974-1977, undated (Box 37)
  - Cowles Comission II, undated (Box 94)
  - Cowles Comission II, undated (Box 94)
  - Crisis Management, 1963-1964, undated (Box 38)
  - Crops, 1939 (Box 94)
  - Currency Devaluation, 1949-1950 (Box 38)
  - D.C. Heath and Co. Stock Market Book, 1969-1970 (Box 95)
  - D.C. Heath and Co., 1975-1976 (Box 38)
  - Dacey, Raymond, 1972-1976 (Box 38)
  - Dagum, Camilo and Estela, 1974-1977 (Box 38)
  - Dartmouth Mathematics Project, 1955 (Box 38)
  - Davis, Blaine, E., 1975 (Box 38)
  - Demand Supply Curves: Reinterpretation, 1939-1946, undated (Box 38)
  - Department of Defense, 1966-1967 (Box 95)
  - Depression of 1930s, 1931 (Box 38)
  - Description of the Economy, 1973-1974, undated (Box 38)
  - Detailed Statistical Materials I, 1939 (Box 95)
  - Detailed Statistical Materials II, 1939 (Box 95)
  - Detailed Statistical Materials III, 1939 (Box 95)
  - Detailed Statistical Materials IV, 1939 (Box 95)
  - Deterrence Strategy Notes, 1959-1971 (Box 38)
  - Dictionary of the History of Ideas Games and Decision Theory, 1969-1970, undated (Box 95)
  - Discount and Interest Rates, 19th-20th Centuries (Box 38)
  - Draper, Theodore: Articles on Dtente, 1974-1976 (Box 38)
  - Druckman, Daniel, 1967-1975, undated (Box 38)
  - Dynamic Behavior, 1976 (Box 38)
  - Dynamic Programming, 1958 (Box 38)
  - E.I. Du Pont de Nemours and Co., 1952, undated (Box 39)
  - Econometric Research Section, 1957 (Box 95)
  - Econometric Society, 1948-1974, undated, 4 folders (Box 39)
  - Economical Design of Hospitals and Samuel Ingwersen, 1971 (Box 39)
  - Economic Development Council of New York City, Paul Busse, 1970-1973, undated (Box 39)
  - Economic Impossibilities (Foreign Affairs), 1974-1976 (Box 39)
  - Economic Theory: Critical Points (See also article "Critical Points in Economic Theory"), 1965-1971, undated (Box 39)
  - Economic Theory: Stability, 1945 (Box 40)
  - Economic Warfare, 1977, Jan. (Box 40)
  - Economics in Crisis, 1973 (Box 40)
  - Edizioni scientifiche e techniche, 1972-1975, undated (Box 40)
  - 11x11 Matrices (Box 95)
  - Energy, 1973-1976, undated (Box 40)
  - English Trip, 1937 (Box 40)
  - Environmental Protection, 1972-1974, undated (Box 40)
  - Error and Economic Measurement, 1976, Aug., undated (Box 40)
  - Essays in Mathematical Economics, edited by Martin Shubik: 1966-1967 (Box 40)
  - Europe 1970-1971 (Box 95)
  - European Conferences and Lectures 1964 (Box 95)
  - European Forum, Alpbach, 1974 (Box 40)
  - European Situation, 1938 (Box 40)
  - European Trip, 1951: 1948-1951, undated (Box 40)
  - European Trip, 1956-1957 (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - European Trip ,1959 (Box 95)
  - European Trip, 1960 (Box 95)
  - European Trip, 1961 (Box 95)
  - European Trip,1962 (Box 95)
  - European Trip, 1972: 1960-1972 (Box 40)
  - European Trip, 1976: 1975-1976 (Box 40)
  - Expansion, 1951-1952, undated (Box 40)
  - Expense Accounts, 1962-1975, undated (Box 40)
  - Experiment in Sciences, 1967 (Box 40)
  - Fairchild Industries, 1975 (Box 40)
  - Fechner, Nicolas, 1973-1977, undated (Box 40)
  - Federal Statistics Users' Conference, 1963 (Box 95)
  - Federal Statistics Users' Conference, 1964 (Box 95)
  - Firm Theory, 1960-1973, undated (Box 40)
  - Fishburn, Peter C., 1970-1977 (Box 40)
  - 500 Years Ahead, 1960 (Box 40)
  - Foreign Banking Systems, 1938, undated (Box 40)
  - Foreign Service Journal Papers, 1960 (Box 95)
  - Foreign Trade Multiplier, circa 1940 (Box 40)
  - Foreign Trade Myths, 1944-1945 (Box 40)
  - Foreign Trade Statistics, 1953 (Box 40)
  - Fortune Magazine, 1961 (Box 95)
  - Fortune Magazine, 1963-1970 (Box 95)
  - Fortune Paper, 1960 (Box 95)
  - Forum for Contemporary History, 1974 (Box 40)
  - Forum for Contemporary History, 1972-1974 (Box 41)
  - Foundation for the Study of Cycles, 1950 (Box 41)
  - Fourier Analysis Project, 1946-1948, undated (Box 41)
  - French Embassy, 1973, undated (Box 41)
  - French Television, 1972-1977 (Box 41)
  - Further Consideration of an Open Expanding Economy Model, 1970 (Box 95)
  - Futuribles (B. de Jouvenel), 1962-1963 (Box 95)
  - Game Definition, 1952-1972, undated (Box 41)
  - Game Theory, 1962-1976, undated (Box 41)
  - Game Theory, (m, n+1) _ (Box 41)
  - Game Theory, (n=2 _=0): 1956-1970, undated (Box 41)
  - Game Theory: Bibliography on Theory of Games and Economic Behavior, 1950 (Box 41)
  - Game Theory: 4 Persons, Single; and Composition: 1949-1974 (Box 41)
  - Game Theory: Further Papers, 1948-1965, undated (Box 41)
  - Game Theory: General Material, 1955-1968, undated (Box 41)
  - Game Theory: History I, 1713-1970, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Game Theory: History II, 1971-1977, undated, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Game Theory: Lecture Notes, General Theory, Former Courses, etc., 1949-1970, undated (Box 42)
  - Game Theory: Non-Zero-Sum, 1948-1970, undated (Box 42)
  - Game Theory: Second All-Union Conference on Game Theory, Theses and Abstracts - USSR, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Game Theory: Three Person, 1948-1975 (Box 42)
  - Game Theory: 3 and n Persons, 1948-1949 (Box 42)
  - Game Theory and Linear Programming: Bibliographies, 1950-1951 (Box 42)
  - Game Theory and Philosophy, 1961-1969, undated (Box 42)
  - Game Theory Book: Notes and Papers, 1957-1969, undated (Box 42)
  - Game Theory Conference,1965 (Box 95)
  - Game Theory Conference,1965 (Box 95)
  - Game Theory Manuscript for Intern. Encyclopedia in the Social Sciences, undated (Box 95)
  - Game Theory Course, 1965-1967: 1953-1954 (Box 42)
  - Games: Integral, 1948-1975, undated (Box 42)
  - Games: New Material, 1950-1973, undated (Box 42)
  - Genensky, Samuel, and Assistance to the Blind, 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - General Equilibrium Theory, 1974 (Box 43)
  - General Motors Consulting, 1965 (Box 95)
  - General Motors, 1973 (Box 43)
  - Geneva Lectures, 1963 (Box 43)
  - German Economic Association Meeting, Bonn, 1972, undated (Box 43)
  - Gold, 1959, undated (Box 95)
  - Graduate Course in Linear Programming, 1955 (Box 95)
  - Gdel, Kurt, 1974-1977 (Box 43)
  - Graham, Frank Dunstone, undated (Box 43)
  - Granger, Clive W., Jr., 1970-1977, undated (Box 43)
  - Great Issues Lectures, New York University, 1973-1975, undated (Box 43)
  - Great Number, 1968 (Box 95)